>> Brian: 我们开始使用 LayoutEffect。
&gt;&gt; Brian: Let's go do useLayoutEffect.
如果你想在 DOM里测量点东西
This is pretty much only useful if you
need to measure something in the DOM,
对吧 ?
right?.
所以我有这个文本区域，对，我可以移动这个，对，
So I have this text area, right,
and I can move this, right,
我在这里测量的是宽度和高度
and I'm measuring up here
what the width and height is.
>> Brian: 我正在使用 useLayoutEffect进行此操作。
&gt;&gt; Brian: And
I'm just doing that with useLayoutEffect.
> > 布莱恩: 这样做的时候，它说只要点击这里就可以了，
&gt;&gt; Brian: So what this is doing, it
says any time that there's a click here,
将宽度设置为 0，这会启动重新呈现，对吗 ?
set the width to 0,
which kicks off a re-render, right?
然后，一旦重新呈现，它就会调用 useLayoutEffect。
And then once that re-render happens
then it'll call useLayoutEffect.
这样我就可以进去渲染
Which allows me to then go in and
render, or
衡量这个元素是什么，我在这里存储的是一个引用，对吧 ?
measure what the element is,
which I'm storing here in a ref, right?
所以注意这有点奇怪对吧
So notice that this is kinda weird, right?
我将宽度设置为 0，对，不是 0，但是
I'm setting width to 0,
right, which is not 0, but
这就能让我去测量它了对吧
this kicks off a re-render which
then allows me to measure it, right?
>> 布莱恩: 这件事有趣的是，他们叫海特 ( 0)。
&gt;&gt; Brian: So what's interesting
about this, they call setwidth(0).
这将启动重新呈现，然后调度 LayoutEffect。
This kicks off a re-render,
which then schedules a LayoutEffect.
然后调用这些设置，然后调用这些 setWidth 和 setHeight。
Which then measures this and
then calls these setWidth and setHeight.
而另一个则是稳定的，对吧 ?
Which kicks off another render,
which then is stable, right?
所以这有两个人在其中。
So this has a couple renders in it.
这听起来很低效，但这是唯一衡量它的方法，对吧 ?
It sounds inefficient, but it's the only
way that actually measure it, right?
库兹你得等它完成测量
Cuz you have to wait for
it to finish measuring.
好消息是在这里两次呼叫呈现功能的时候
And the good news is while it calls
the render function twice here,
这个 LayoutEffect 组件两次，它实际上只画一次。
this LayoutEffect component twice,
it actually only paints once, so.
>> Brian: 再次，如果您正在为 jQuery 或 D3 进行度量之类的操作，并且
&gt;&gt; Brian: Again, if you're doing something
like measuring stuff for jQuery or D3 and
把它变成别的东西你就是这样做的
passing it into something else,
this is how you would do it.
但通常你不一定要这样做。
But typically you would not
necessarily do that here.
这就像使用 LayoutEffect一样，就像效果一样。
Now this is just like,
useLayoutEffect, is just like effect.
它的工作方式是一样的，在这里也有同样的排列。
It works exactly the same way,
it has the same array here, as well.
所以如果我这样做，就不会再采取任何措施了，对吗 ?
So if I did this, this will no
longer measure anything, right?
0 就 0 ，对吧 ?
It will send to 0 and
leave it at 0, right?
所以工作方式也是一样的。
So works exactly the same way.
是使用效果的唯一区别是
Really the only difference
between useEffect and
useLayoutEffect 是您执行 useEffect 的预定时间。
useLayoutEffect is if you do
useEffect it's scheduled for later.
几乎是立即的，对，但是
Which is almost immediate, right, but
在调度和发生之间进行技术上的异步
it's technically asynchronous
between scheduling and happening.
LayoutEffect 在技术上是同步的，对吧 ?
Whereas LayoutEffect is
technically synchronous, right?
发生了 Render ， LayoutEffect 发生并且
Render happens then
LayoutEffect happens and
它是同步的它们就在彼此之间对吧
it's synchronous,
they're right next to each other, right?
这就是区别
That's the difference.
> > 布莱恩: 另一个有趣的事情是我
&gt;&gt; Brian: Another interesting
thing here to call out here is I
用 el 来做一个 useRef 对吧
do a useRef right here using el, right?
然后我就在说 textarea 和 ref =
And then here,
I'm just saying textarea and ref = .
这将执行的操作是将实际的 DOM 组件实际存储在此处。
What this will do is it'll actually
store the actual DOM component here.
所以如果我说的是 console.log ( el) ，
So if I said console.log(el) right here,
它会把这个组件给我
it would actually give
me this component here.
我们就这么做吧
Let's just do it.
因此，如果我说控制台， >> Brian: console.log(el)，
So if I say console,
&gt;&gt; Brian: console.log(el),
可能是第一次没定义，是吧 ?
it'll be probably undefined
the first time, which it is, right?
它会第一次出现但它还不存在
Cuz it'll render the first time and
it doesn't exist yet.
然后第二次告诉我，好吧，这是一个文本区域。
And then the second time it'll tell me,
okay, this is a text area.